<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Henry's SpiritLine</title><link href="http://henrychenv.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://henrychenv.github.io/feeds/english.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://henrychenv.github.io/</id><updated>2016-02-21T20:36:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>[TED] Why you will fail to have a great career</title><link href="http://henrychenv.github.io/why-you-will-fail-to-have-a-great-career.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-02-21T20:36:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Henry Chen</name></author><id>tag:henrychenv.github.io,2016-02-21:why-you-will-fail-to-have-a-great-career.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;div class="toc"&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to discuss with you this afternoon why you&amp;rsquo;re going to fail to have a
great career. (Laughter)
今天下午我想和你们讨论一下，你为什么不会成就伟业。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m an economist. I do dismal. End of the day, it&amp;rsquo;s ready for dismal remarks. I
only want to talk to those of you who want a great career. I know some of you
have already decided you want a good career. You&amp;rsquo;re going to fail,
too-(Laughter)-because-Goodness, you&amp;rsquo;re all cheery about failing. (Laughter)
Canadian group, undoubtedly. (Laughter) Those trying to have good careers are
going to fail, because, really, good jobs are now disappearing. There are great
jobs and great careers, and then there are the high-workload, high-stress,
bloodsucking, soul-destroying kinds of jobs, and practically nothing in
between.
我是个经济学家。我让人心情低落。一天过完了，准备好听听让人心情低落的评论。我只想和你们想要成就伟业的那些人谈。
我知道你们有些人已经决定了，你们想要一个成功的事业。你们也会失败的——（笑声）——，因为－天呐，你们听到失败都这么高兴。（笑声）无疑是加拿大人。（笑声）想事业有成的人会失败，因为，真的，现在好工作都在消失。有好工作，和好事业，也有工作量大，压力大，吸食血液，侵蚀灵魂的那种工作，而且几乎没有工作能好点的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So the people looking for good jobs are going to fail. I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about
those looking for great jobs, great careers, and why you&amp;rsquo;re going to, why
you&amp;rsquo;re going to fail. First reason is that no matter how many times people tell
you, &amp;ldquo;If you want a great career, you have to pursue your passion, you have to
pursue your dreams, you have to pursue, the greatest fascination in your life,&amp;rdquo;
you hear it again and again and then you decide not to do it. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter
how many times you download Steven J.&amp;rsquo;s Stanford commencement address, you
still look at it and decide not to do it.
所以想找好工作的人会失败。我谈谈那些寻找伟业的人，你们为什么要寻找，为什么会失败。第一个原因是不管多少次别人告诉你，“如果你想成就伟业，你就必须追随你的热忱，你必须追随你的梦想，你必须追随，你人生中最大的吸引，“
你听过这句话一遍又一遍，然后你决定，不去这样做。不管你下载多少次，Steven
J在斯坦福大学的开学演讲，你还是看看然后决定不去做。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not quite sure why you decide not to do it. You&amp;rsquo;re too lazy to do it. It&amp;rsquo;s
too hard. You&amp;rsquo;re afraid if you look for your passion and don&amp;rsquo;t find it, you&amp;rsquo;ll
feel like you&amp;rsquo;re an idiot, so then you make excuses about why you&amp;rsquo;re not going
to look for your passion. And they are excuses, ladies and gentlemen. We&amp;rsquo;re
going to go through a whole long list, your creativity, and thinking of excuses
not to do what you really need to do if you want to have a great career.
我不太确定你为什么决定不去做。你太懒了。这事太难。你害怕如果你去寻找梦想然后找不到，你会觉得你像个白痴，所以你给自己找借口，为什么你不去追寻你的梦想。这些都是借口，女士们先生们。我们要列一个长单子，你的创造力，想想你不去做成就伟业该做的事情的借口。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, for example, one of your great excuses is, &amp;ldquo;Well, great careers are really
and truly, for most people, just a matter of luck, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to stand
around, I&amp;rsquo;m going to try to be lucky, and if I&amp;rsquo;m lucky, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a great
career. If not, I&amp;rsquo;ll have a good career.&amp;rdquo; But a good career is an
impossibility, so that&amp;rsquo;s not going to work.
所以，举例来说，你众多借口之一是，
“嗯，伟业实际上对于大多数人来说，只是运气问题，所以我就在这待着，我就试试做那个幸运的人，然后如果我真幸运的话，我就能成就伟业。如果不能，我就找个还不错的事业。”
但是没有还不错的事业，所以这个行不通。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, your other excuse is, &amp;ldquo;Yes, there are special people who pursue their
passions, but they are geniuses. They are Steven J. I&amp;rsquo;m not a genius. When I
was five, I thought I was a genius, but my professors have beaten that idea out
of my head long since.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter) Mm? &amp;ldquo;And now I know I am completely
competent.&amp;rdquo; Now, you see, if this was 1950, being completely competent, that
would have given you a great career. But guess what? This is almost 2012, and
saying to the world, &amp;ldquo;I am totally, completely competent,&amp;rdquo; is damning yourself
with the faintest of praise.
然后，你还有其他借口：“是的，有那些与众不同的人，
追寻自己的梦想，但是他们是天才。他们是Steven J.
我不是天才。我五岁的时候以为自己是天才，但是我的教授们早就把这个念头，打消了。”（笑声）嗯？
“然后现在我知道自己完全有能力。” 现在你看，如果这是在1950年，
完全有能力，就能让你成就伟业。但是你知道么？现在几乎是2012年了，对世界说“我完全，绝对，有能力，”就是用最无力的称赞谴责你自己。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And then, of course, another excuse: &amp;ldquo;Well, I would do this, I would do this,
but, but, well, after all, I&amp;rsquo;m not weird. Everybody knows that people who
pursue their passions are somewhat obsessive. A little strange? Mm? Mm? Okay?
You know, a fine line between madness and genius. I&amp;rsquo;m not weird. I&amp;rsquo;ve read
Steven J.&amp;rsquo;s biography. Oh my goodness. I am not that person. I am nice. I am
normal. I&amp;rsquo;m a nice, normal person, and nice, normal people don&amp;rsquo;t have passion.
Ah. But I still want a great career. I&amp;rsquo;m not prepared to pursue my passion, so
I know what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do, because I have, I have a solution, I have a
strategy. It&amp;rsquo;s the one Mommy and Daddy told me about. Mommy and Daddy told me
that if I worked hard, I&amp;rsquo;d have a good career. So, if you work hard and have a
good career, if you work really, really, really hard, you&amp;rsquo;ll have a great
career. Doesn&amp;rsquo;t that, like, mathematically make sense?&amp;rdquo; Hmm. Not. (Laughter)
But you&amp;rsquo;ve managed to talk yourself into that.
然后，当然，另外一个借口：“嗯，我会做这个，我会做这个，但是，但是，
嗯，毕竟，我不是个怪人。每个人都知道那些追寻自己梦想的人，都多少有点强迫症。有点奇怪？嗯？嗯？好吧？你知道的，疯子和天才一线之隔。
我不是个怪人。我读过Steven
J的传记。我的天呐。我不是那种人。我是好人。我是正常人。我是正常的好人，而且正常的好人，没有梦想。啊。但是我还是想要成就伟业。我还没准备好去追寻梦想，所以我知道，我要做什么，因为我有办法，我有策略。就是爸爸妈妈告诉过我的那个。爸爸妈妈告诉我说如果我努力工作，
我会有个不错的事业。所以，如果你努力工作，而且有个不错的事业，如果你工作特别特别特别努力，你就能成就伟业。这在数学上不是也成立么？”嗯&amp;hellip;不是的。（笑声）但是你还是让自己信了这话。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You know what? Here&amp;rsquo;s a little secret. You want to work? You want to work
really, really, really hard? You know what? You&amp;rsquo;ll succeed. The world will give
you the opportunity to work really, really, really, really hard, but are you so
sure that that&amp;rsquo;s going to give you a great career when all the evidence is to
the contrary?
你知道么？这有一个小秘密。你想工作？你想工作特别特别特别努力？你知道么？你会成功的。这个世界会给你机会去工作得特别特别特别努力，
但是你就那么确信这能让你成就伟业，即使所有的证据都指向另一边？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s assume, let&amp;rsquo;s deal with those of you who are trying to find your
passion. You actually understand that you really had better do it, never mind
the excuses. You&amp;rsquo;re trying to find your passion, and you&amp;rsquo;re so happy. You found
something you&amp;rsquo;re interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="code-line"&gt;    所以咱们假设，咱们来处理一下你们当中，想追寻梦想的人。你实际上明白你最好这么做。抛开借口。你试图找到你的梦想，而且你这么快乐。你找到了你感兴趣的事。&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I have an interest! I have an interest! You tell me. You say, &amp;ldquo;I have an
interest!&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;That&amp;rsquo;s wonderful! And what, what are you trying to tell me?
That you — &amp;ldquo; &amp;ldquo;Well, I have an interest.&amp;rdquo; I say, &amp;ldquo;Do you have passion?&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;I have
an interest,&amp;rdquo; you say. Your interest is compared to what? &amp;ldquo;Well, I&amp;rsquo;m interested
in this.&amp;rdquo; And what about the rest of humanity&amp;rsquo;s activities? &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m not interested
in them.&amp;rdquo; You&amp;rsquo;ve looked at them all, have you? &amp;ldquo;No. Not exactly.&amp;rdquo;
我有个兴趣！我有个兴趣！你告诉我。你说，“我有个兴趣！”我说，“太好了！”你想告诉我什么呢？
“嗯，我有个兴趣。”我说，“你有热忱么？”， “我有兴趣，”你说。你的兴趣和什么比较？
“嗯，我对这个感兴趣。”那其他一切的人类活动呢？
“我对那些没兴趣。”你把那些都看过一遍了？“没有。不完全是。”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Passion is your greatest love. Passion is the thing that will help you create
the highest expression of your talent. Passion, interest-it&amp;rsquo;s not the same
thing. Are you really going to go to your sweetie and say, &amp;ldquo;Marry me! You&amp;rsquo;re
interesting.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter) Won&amp;rsquo;t happen. Won&amp;rsquo;t happen, and you will die alone.
(Laughter)
热忱是你最高程度的热爱。热忱是能帮助你最好地成就自己才华的事情。热忱，兴趣——不是一回事。你真的会去找你的甜心然后说：“嫁给我吧！你很有意思。”（笑声）不会发生的。不会发生，然后你会孤独终老。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you want, what you want, what you want, is passion. It is beyond interest.
You need 20 interests, and then one of them, one of them might grab you, one of
them might engage you more than anything else, and then you may have found your
greatest love in comparison to all the other things that interest you, and
that&amp;rsquo;s what passion is.
你想要的，你想要的，你想要的，是热忱。它超越兴趣。你需要20个兴趣，然后它们其中一个，其中一个会抓住你，让你燃起激情。
然后你就找到了与其他事情相比之下，你最大的热爱，那就是你的热忱。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a friend, proposed to his sweetie. He was an economically rational
person. He said to his sweetie, &amp;ldquo;Let us marry. Let us merge our
interests.&amp;rdquo;(Laughter)
我有个朋友，向他女友求婚。
他是个会过日子的人。他对他女友说：“咱们结婚吧。让咱们融合利益。”（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes he did. &amp;ldquo;I love you truly,&amp;rdquo; he said. &amp;ldquo;I love you deeply. I love you more
than any other woman I&amp;rsquo;ve ever encountered. I love you more than Mary, Jane,
Susie, Penelope, Ingrid, Gertrude, Gretel-I was on a German exchange program
then.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter) &amp;ldquo;I love you more than&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; All right! She left the room
halfway through his enumeration of his love for her. After he got over his
surprise at being, you know, turned down, he concluded he&amp;rsquo;d had a narrow escape
from marrying an irrational person, although he did make a note to himself that
the next time he proposed, it was perhaps not necessary to enumerate all of the
women he had auditioned for the part. (Laughter)
是的，他这么说的。“我真心爱你，”他说，“我深深爱着你。我爱你，胜过其他任何女人。我爱你胜过Mary,
Jane, Susie, Penelope,Ingrid, Gertrude, Gretel——
我那时候在一个德国的交换项目里。”（笑声）“我爱你胜过——”，
好的！她在他列举到一半的时候，离开了房间。在他从被拒绝的惊讶中缓过来之后，他总结了他刚刚成功逃离，和一个不理性的人结婚的厄运。虽然他也对自己说，下次求婚的时候，不必要列举所有过往的女朋友。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the point stands. You must look for alternatives so that you find your
destiny, or are you afraid of the word &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo;? Does the word &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo; scare
you? That&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re talking about, and if you don&amp;rsquo;t find the highest
expression of your talent, if you settle for &amp;ldquo;interesting,&amp;rdquo; what the hell ever
that means, do you know what will happen at the end of your long life? Your
friends and family will be gathered in the cemetery, and there, beside your
gravesite will be a tombstone, and inscribed on that tombstone, it will say,
&amp;ldquo;Here lies a distinguished engineer who invented Velcro.&amp;rdquo; But what that
tombstone should have said, in an alternative lifetime, what it should have
said if it was your highest expression of talent, was, &amp;ldquo;Here lies the last
Nobel Laureate in Physics, who formulated the Grand Unified Field Theory and
demonstrated the practicality of warp drive.&amp;rdquo;(Laughter)
但是这个论点是成立的。你必须寻找各种选择，才能找到命中注定的那个，或者你害怕“命中注定”这个词么？
“命中注定”这个词吓着你么？这就是我们要谈的，而且如果你找不到，你才能的最高表达，如果你在，“有意思”这里止步不前，不管这他妈的是什么意思，你知道在你漫长的一生即将结束的时候会发生什么吗？你的亲友们聚集在墓地里，在这，你的坟边上有个墓碑，这个墓碑上刻着字，说，“此地长眠着一位发明了Velcro的杰出工程师。”但是这个墓碑上也应该刻着，在一个平行时空里，如果这是你才能的最高表达它就应该刻着，“此地长眠着一位诺贝尔物理学奖得主，他规范了‘大统一场论’并且示范了曲速引擎的实用性。”（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Velcro, indeed. (Laughter)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span class="code-line"&gt;    Velcro，的确。（笑声）&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;One was a great career. One was a missed opportunity. But then, there are some
of you, in spite of all these excuses, you will find, you will find your
passion, and you&amp;rsquo;ll still fail.
一个是伟业。一个是失掉的机会。但是，你们当中有些人，抛开这些借口，你们会找到，你们会找到自己的热忱，然后你们还是失败了。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re going to fail, because, because you&amp;rsquo;re not going to do it, because you
will have invented a new excuse, any excuse to fail to take action, and this
excuse I&amp;rsquo;ve heard so many times. &amp;ldquo;Yes, I would pursue a great career, but I
value human relationships more than accomplishment. I want to be a great
friend. I want to be a great spouse. I want to be a great parent, and I will
not sacrifice them on the altar of great accomplishment.&amp;rdquo;(Laughter)
你会失败，因为，因为你不会着手去做，因为你会想出新的借口，任何让你只说不做的借口，而且这个借口，我已经听过很多次了。“是的，我会追求一番伟业，但是相比成就，我更看重人与人之间的关系。我想做一个好朋友。我想做一个好伴侣。我想做一个好父母，而且我不会为伟大的成就而牺牲这些。”（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you want me to say? Now, do you really want me to say now, tell you,
&amp;ldquo;Really, I swear I don&amp;rsquo;t kick children.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter) Hmm? Look at the worldview
you&amp;rsquo;ve given yourself. You&amp;rsquo;re a hero no matter what, and I, by suggesting, ever
so delicately, that you might want a great career, must hate children. I don&amp;rsquo;t
hate children. I don&amp;rsquo;t kick them. Yes, there was a little kid wandering through
this building when I came here, and no, I didn&amp;rsquo;t kick him. (Laughter)
你们想让我说什么？现在，你们真的想让我说，告诉你们，“真的，我发誓我不踢小孩。”（笑声）嗯？看看你给自己定的世界观。无论如何你都是个英雄，然而我，通过暗示，这么小心翼翼地，说你可能想要成就伟业，一定痛恨小孩。我不恨小孩。我不踢他们。是的，刚才我来的时候有个小孩走过来，
我没踢他。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course, I had to tell him that the building was for adults only and to get out.
He mumbled something about his mother, and I told him she&amp;rsquo;d probably find him
outside anyway. Last time I saw him, he was on the stairs crying. (Laughter)
What a wimp. (Laughter)
当然，我不得不告诉他这个楼是给大人的，他得出去。他含糊地说他妈妈什么的，然后我跟他说他妈估计在外面找他呢。我上次看到他的时候他正在台阶上哭呢。（笑声）真是个懦夫。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what do you mean? That&amp;rsquo;s what you expect me to say. You really think, you
really think it&amp;rsquo;s appropriate that you should actually take children and use
them as a shield? You know what will happen someday, you, you ideal parent,
you? The kid will come to you someday and say, &amp;ldquo;I know what I want to be. I
know what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do with my life.&amp;rdquo; You are so happy. It&amp;rsquo;s the
conversation a parent wants to hear, because your kid&amp;rsquo;s good in math, and you
know you&amp;rsquo;re going to like what comes next. Says your kid, &amp;ldquo;I have decided I
want to be a magician. I want to perform magic tricks on the stage.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter)
但是你是什么意思？这就是你们期待我说的。你真的认为，你真的认为，拿小孩当挡箭牌，合适吗？你知道有一天会发生什么，你，完美的父母，对吗？你的孩子有一天会跟你说，
“我知道我想做什么。我知道我想怎么度过一生。”你特别高兴。这种对话父母最爱听了，因为你的孩子数学好，而且你知道你会爱听你孩子接下来的话。你孩子说，“我决定了，我想做个魔术师。我想在舞台上表演魔术。”（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And what do you say? You say, you say, &amp;ldquo;Umm &amp;hellip; that&amp;rsquo;s risky, kid. Might fail,
kid. Don&amp;rsquo;t make a lot of money at that, kid. You know, I don&amp;rsquo;t know, kid, you
should think about that again, kid, you&amp;rsquo;re so good at math, why don&amp;rsquo;t you &amp;hellip; &amp;rdquo;
然后你说什么？ 你说，你说，
“嗯..……那样比较不保险，孩子。有可能会失败，孩子。挣不了大钱，孩子。你知道的，我不知道，孩子，
你应该再想想，孩子，你数学这么好，为什么不——”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the kid interrupts you, and says, &amp;ldquo;But it is my dream. It is my dream to do
this.&amp;rdquo; And what are you going to say? You know what you&amp;rsquo;re going to say? &amp;ldquo;Look
kid. I had a dream once, too, but&amp;hellip;but.&amp;rdquo; So how are you going to finish the
sentence with your &amp;ldquo;but&amp;rdquo;? &amp;ldquo;&amp;hellip; But. I had a dream too, once, kid, but I was
afraid to pursue it.&amp;rdquo; Or, are you going to tell him this? &amp;ldquo;I had a dream once,
kid. But then you were born.&amp;rdquo; (Laughter)
然后你孩子打断你，说：“但是那是我的梦想。我梦想就是成为魔术师。”然后你要说什么？你知道你要说什么吗？“你看，孩子，我过去也有过梦想。但是——但是。”所以你想怎么用“但是”结束你的句子？
“……但是，我过去也有过梦想，孩子，但是我没敢去追随。”还是，你想告诉他这个？“我过去有梦想，孩子。但是之后你出生了。”（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Laughter) (Applause)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;（笑声）（掌声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you, do you really want to use your family, do you really ever want to look
at your spouse and your kid and see your jailers? There was something you could
have said to your kid when he or she said, &amp;ldquo;I have a dream.&amp;rdquo; You could have
said, looked the kid in the face, and said, &amp;ldquo;Go for it, kid, just like I did.&amp;rdquo;
But you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to say that because you didn&amp;rsquo;t. So you can&amp;rsquo;t. (Laughter)
你真的，真的想利用你的家庭，你真的想把你的伴侣，
和你的孩子当成狱卒吗？你其实可以这么跟你孩子讲。当他／她说“我有个梦想”的时候，你可以说，面对你的孩子，说，“去追随它吧，孩子，就像我那样。”
但是你没法那么说，因为你没去追随梦想。所以你不能那么说。（笑声）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And so the sins of the parents are visited on the poor children. Why will you
seek refuge in human relationships as your excuse not to find and pursue your
passion? You know why. In your heart of hearts, you know why, and I&amp;rsquo;m being
deadly serious. You know why you would get all warm and fuzzy and wrap yourself
up in human relationships. It is because you are -You know what you are.
然后父母的罪恶，就在可怜的孩子们身上应验了。你为什么把人际关系当成你不去追随你的热忱的借口？你自己知道为什么。在你内心的内心，你知道为什么，而且我现在非常严肃。你知道你为什么会在人际关系中层层包裹自己。这是因为你是——你知道你是什么。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re afraid to pursue your passion. You&amp;rsquo;re afraid to look ridiculous. You&amp;rsquo;re
afraid to try. You&amp;rsquo;re afraid you may fail. Great friend, great spouse, great
parent, great career. Is that not a package? Is that not who you are? How can
you be one without the other? But you&amp;rsquo;re afraid.
你不敢去追求梦想。你害怕自己看起来像个疯子。你不敢去尝试。你害怕失败。好朋友，好伴侣，好父母，伟业。不是打包在一起的吗？这难道不是你？你怎么能符合其中一个却不符合另一个？但是你害怕。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that&amp;rsquo;s why you&amp;rsquo;re not going to have a great career, unless - unless, that
most evocative of all English words &amp;ndash; unless. But the unless word is also
attached to that other, most terrifying phrase, &amp;ldquo;If only I had &amp;hellip; &amp;ldquo; &amp;ldquo;If only I
had &amp;hellip; &amp;rdquo; If you ever have that thought ricocheting in your brain, it will hurt
a lot.
这就是为什么你不会成就伟业，除非——除非，最引人回忆的词——除非。但是除非这个词和另外一个，
最可怕的短语是连着的，“如果我当初……”
“如果我当初……”如果你曾经有过这个想法在你脑海里回旋，它会特别伤人。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, those are the many reasons why you are going to fail to have a great
career, unless &amp;hellip;
所以，这些就是，你为什么不能成就伟业，的众多原因。 除非……“&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless.
除非。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you. (Applause)
谢谢。（掌声）&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="ted"></category><category term="dream"></category></entry><entry><title>[TED] Embrace The Near Win</title><link href="http://henrychenv.github.io/ted-embrace-the-near-win.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2016-01-30T02:00:00+08:00</updated><author><name>Henry Chen</name></author><id>tag:henrychenv.github.io,2016-01-20:ted-embrace-the-near-win.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I feel so fortunate that my first job was working at the Museum of Modern Art on a retrospective of painter Elizabeth Murray. I learned so much from her. After the curator Robert Storr selected all the paintings from her lifetime body of work, I loved looking at the paintings from the 1970s. There were some motifs and elements that would come up again later in her life. I remember asking her what she thought of those early works. If you didn&amp;rsquo;t know they were hers, you might not have been able to guess.She told me that a few didn&amp;rsquo;t quite meet her own mark for what she wanted them to be. One of the works, in fact, so didn&amp;rsquo;t meet her mark, she had set it out in the trash in her studio, and her neighbor had taken it because she saw its value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In that moment, my view of success and creativity changed. I realized that success is a moment, but what we&amp;rsquo;re always celebrating is creativity and mastery. But this is the thing: What gets us to convert success into mastery? This is a question I&amp;rsquo;ve long asked myself. I think it comes when we start to valuethe gift of a near win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started to understand this when I went on one cold May day to watch a set of varsity archers, all women as fate would have it, at the northern tip of Manhattan at Columbia&amp;rsquo;s Baker Athletics Complex. I wanted to see what&amp;rsquo;s called archer&amp;rsquo;s paradox, the idea that in order to actually hit your target, you have to aim at something slightly skew from it. I stood and watched as the coach drove up these women in this gray van, and they exited with this kind of relaxed focus. One held a half-eaten ice cream cone in one handand arrows in the left with yellow fletching. And they passed me and smiled, but they sized me up as theymade their way to the turf, and spoke to each other not with words but with numbers, degrees, I thought,positions for how they might plan to hit their target. I stood behind one archer as her coach stood in between us to maybe assess who might need support, and watched her, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand how even one was going to hit the ten ring. The ten ring from the standard 75-yard distance, it looks as small as a matchstick tip held out at arm&amp;rsquo;s length. And this is while holding 50 pounds of draw weight on each shot. She first hit a seven, I remember, and then a nine, and then two tens, and then the next arrow didn&amp;rsquo;t even hit the target. And I saw that gave her more tenacity, and she went after it again and again. For three hours this went on. At the end of the practice, one of the archers was so taxed that she lied out on the ground just star-fished, her head looking up at the sky, trying to find what T.S. Eliot might call that still point of the turning world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s so rare in American culture, there&amp;rsquo;s so little that&amp;rsquo;s vocational about it anymore, to look at what doggedness looks like with this level of exactitude, what it means to align your body posture for three hours in order to hit a target, pursuing a kind of excellence in obscurity. But I stayed because I realized I was witnessing what&amp;rsquo;s so rare to glimpse, that difference between success and mastery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So success is hitting that ten ring, but mastery is knowing that it means nothing if you can&amp;rsquo;t do it again and again. Mastery is not just the same as excellence, though. It&amp;rsquo;s not the same as success, which I see as an event, a moment in time, and a label that the world confers upon you. Mastery is not a commitment to a goal but to a constant pursuit. What gets us to do this, what get us to forward thrust more is to value the near win. How many times have we designated something a classic, a masterpiece even, while its creator considers it hopelessly unfinished, riddled with difficulties and flaws, in other words, a near win?Elizabeth Murray surprised me with her admission about her earlier paintings. Painter Paul Cézanne so often thought his works were incomplete that he would deliberately leave them aside with the intention of picking them back up again, but at the end of his life, the result was that he had only signed 10 percent of his paintings. His favorite novel was &amp;ldquo;The [Unknown] Masterpiece&amp;rdquo; by Honoré de Balzac, and he felt the protagonist was the painter himself. Franz Kafka saw incompletion when others would find only works to praise, so much so that he wanted all of his diaries, manuscripts, letters and even sketches burned upon his death. His friend refused to honor the request, and because of that, we now have all the works we now do by Kafka: &amp;ldquo;America,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;The Trial&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Castle,&amp;rdquo; a work so incomplete it even stops mid-sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The pursuit of mastery, in other words, is an ever-onward almost. &amp;ldquo;Lord, grant that I desire more than I can accomplish,&amp;rdquo; Michelangelo implored, as if to that Old Testament God on the Sistine Chapel, and he himself was that Adam with his finger outstretched and not quite touching that God&amp;rsquo;s hand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mastery is in the reaching, not the arriving. It&amp;rsquo;s in constantly wanting to close that gap between where you are and where you want to be. Mastery is about sacrificing for your craft and not for the sake of crafting your career. How many inventors and untold entrepreneurs live out this phenomenon? We see it even in the life of the indomitable Arctic explorer Ben Saunders, who tells me that his triumphs are not merely the result of a grand achievement, but of the propulsion of a lineage of near wins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thrive when we stay at our own leading edge. It&amp;rsquo;s a wisdom understood by Duke Ellington, who said that his favorite song out of his repertoire was always the next one, always the one he had yet to compose. Part of the reason that the near win is inbuilt to mastery is because the greater our proficiency,the more clearly we might see that we don&amp;rsquo;t know all that we thought we did. It&amp;rsquo;s called the Dunning–Kruger effect. The Paris Review got it out of James Baldwin when they asked him, &amp;ldquo;What do you think increases with knowledge?&amp;rdquo; and he said, &amp;ldquo;You learn how little you know.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Success motivates us, but a near win can propel us in an ongoing quest. One of the most vivid examples of this comes when we look at the difference between Olympic silver medalists and bronze medalists after a competition. Thomas Gilovich and his team from Cornell studied this difference and found that the frustration silver medalists feel compared to bronze, who are typically a bit more happy to have just not received fourth place and not medaled at all, gives silver medalists a focus on follow-up competition. We see it even in the gambling industry that once picked up on this phenomenon of the near win and created these scratch-off tickets that had a higher than average rate of near wins and so compelled people to buy more tickets that they were called heart-stoppers, and were set on a gambling industry set of abuses in Britain in the 1970s. The reason the near win has a propulsion is because it changes our view of the landscape and puts our goals, which we tend to put at a distance, into more proximate vicinity to where we stand. If I ask you to envision what a great day looks like next week, you might describe it in more general terms. But if I ask you to describe a great day at TED tomorrow, you might describe it with granular, practical clarity. And this is what a near win does. It gets us to focus on what, right now, we plan to do to address that mountain in our sights. It&amp;rsquo;s Jackie Joyner-Kersee, who in 1984 missed taking the gold in the heptathlon by one third of a second, and her husband predicted that would give her the tenacity she needed in follow-up competition. In 1988, she won the gold in the heptathlon and set a record of 7,291 points, a score that no athlete has come very close to since.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We thrive not when we&amp;rsquo;ve done it all, but when we still have more to do. I stand here thinking and wondering about all the different ways that we might even manufacture a near win in this room, how your lives might play this out, because I think on some gut level we do know this. We know that we thrive when we stay at our own leading edge, and it&amp;rsquo;s why the deliberate incomplete is inbuilt into creation myths. In Navajo culture, some craftsmen and women would deliberately put an imperfection in textiles and ceramics. It&amp;rsquo;s what&amp;rsquo;s called a spirit line, a deliberate flaw in the pattern to give the weaver or maker a way out, but also a reason to continue making work. Masters are not experts because they take a subject to its conceptual end. They&amp;rsquo;re masters because they realize that there isn&amp;rsquo;t one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it occurred to me, as I thought about this, why the archery coach told me at the end of that practice,out of earshot of his archers, that he and his colleagues never feel they can do enough for their team,never feel there are enough visualization techniques and posture drills to help them overcome those constant near wins. It didn&amp;rsquo;t sound like a complaint, exactly, but just a way to let me know, a kind of tender admission, to remind me that he knew he was giving himself over to a voracious, unfinished paththat always required more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We build out of the unfinished idea, even if that idea is our former self. This is the dynamic of mastery.Coming close to what you thought you wanted can help you attain more than you ever dreamed you could. It&amp;rsquo;s what I have to imagine Elizabeth Murray was thinking when I saw her smiling at those early paintings one day in the galleries. Even if we created utopias, I believe we would still have the incomplete. Completion is a goal, but we hope it is never the end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="TED"></category><category term="English"></category></entry></feed>